<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<list>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhavapraśna.</title>
<note>Strickmann, CPP, p. 117.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhayakarīdhāraṇī.</title>
<note>Matsunami, p. 287.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhayakumārasya Padmottaratathāgatavyākaraṇa.</title>
<note>Matsunami, p. 233.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K702</rkts>
<title>Abhayapradā-nāma-aparājita</title>
<note>'Phags pa gzhan gyis mi thub pa mi 'jigs pa sbyin pa.  Tôh. no. 708 (also, no. 928).  Dergé Kanjur, vol. TSA, folios 176v.1 177v.6.  Tr. by Prajñāvarman and Ye shes sde.</note>
<note>EoB under the title "Abhayatādāna-nāma-aparājita."</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidhammamūlaṭīkā.</title>
<note>Nakamura, p. 119.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidhammatthasaṅgraha.</title>
<note>Nakamura, p. 119, 126.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidhānappadīpikā.</title>
<note>EoB.  The most authoritative of the old Pāli synonym lexicons, traditionally attributed to Moggallāna, it held the same place in Pāli literature as the Amarakoṣa did in Sanskrit.</note>
<note>Swami Dwarkidas Shastri, ed., Abhidhānappadīpikā and Ekakkharakosa, Bauddhabharti (Varanasi 1981).</note>
<note>Jinadasa Liyanaratne, South Asian Flora as notelected in the Twelfth Century Pāli Lexicon Abhidhānappadīpikā, Journal of the Pali Text Society, vol. 20 (1994), pp. 43 161.</note>
<note>Bhikkhu Medagama Nandawansa, Abhidhānappadīpikā: A Study of the Text and Its Commentary, Bhandarkar Oriental Research Institute (Pune 2000), in 558 pages.</note>
<note>Abhidhānappadīpikā and Ekakharakośa, Bauddha Bhārati series nos. 14 15 (Varanasi ????).  Pāli Sanskrit Hindi dictionary.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K369</rkts>
<title>Abhidhānottaratantra</title>
<note>Mngon par brjod pa'i rgyud bla ma.  Tôh. no. 369.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. KA, folios 247r.1 370r.7.  Tr. by Ānanda and Lo chung (but see the colophon).  69 chapters.  Evidently some pnoteer the slightly different Tibetan title Nges par brjod pa'i rgyud bla ma, or more shortly, Nges brjod bla ma.</note>
<note>The colophon reads:  mngon par brjod pa'i rgyud bla ma'i bla ma las gsang bas gsang ba'i bde mchog gi rgyud kyi rgyal po chen po zhes bya ba rdzogs so //  rgya gar gyi mkhan po paṇḍi ta chen po dī paṅka ra shrī dznyā na dang / bod kyi lo tsā ba chen po dge slong rin chen bzang pos bsgyur cing zhus te gtan la phab pa / phyis paṇḍi ta chen po dznyā na shrī dang / lo tsā ba khyung po chos kyi brtson 'grus kyis kyang zhus pa'o //  // phyis paṇḍi ta ā nanda dang / lo chung gis chad lhag rnams bsabs nas / zhus dag byas nas legs par bcos te gtan la phab // 'di las zab pa med do //  Dīpaṅkaraśrījñāna (Atiśa) and Jñānaśrī (11th century) are mentioned here.</note>
<note>Martin M. Kalff, Selected Chapters from the Abhidhānottara Tantra: The Union of Female and Male Deities, doctoral dissertation, Columbia University (New York 1979).</note>
<note>EoB under "Abhidhānottarottara."</note>
<note>I am not certain who the translator Lo chung ought to be, but the most likely choice would be Lo chung Legs pa'i shes rab.</note>
<note>Palmleaf Sanskrit manuscript in 156 folios belonging to the Nor bu gling ka.  Here the title reads Śrīherukābhidhānamahātantrarāja...mahāsaṃvara.  Tibetan version of the title given as Bde mchog sdom pa 'byung ba'i rgyud le'u sum cu rtsa gsum gyi bdag nyid.  KCDS, p. 16.</note>
<note>Palmleaf Sanskrit manuscript now belonging to the Nor bu gling ka.  Sanskrit title given as Śrīherukābhidhānamahātantrarājatrilakṣādhṛta (Tibetan given as Sdom pa 'byung ba'i rgyud gnang ba).  KCDS, p. 26 (see also p. 35).</note>
<note>Sanskrit palmleaf manuscript now belonging to Potala.  Title given as Hevajrābhidhānaśrīcakrasaṃvara...  I imagine it should read Herukābhidhāna...  Listed as a text from Zhwa lu Monastery.  KCDS, p. 131.</note>
<note>A 48 folio Sanskrit palmleaf manuscript now belonging to Potala, formerly of Ngor Monastery.  Here the title is given as "Śrīherukābhidhānemahātantrarājaṃ."  KCDS, p. 158.</note>
<note>Outline of 67 chapters.  Matsunami, pp. 245 247.</note>
<note>BSM, p. 2 (MBB I 25).  A 92 folio manuscript dated 1743.  Also, BSM, p. 6 (MBB I 100), a 194 folio palmleaf manuscript dated 1138 CE.  BSM, p. 13 (MBB II 89), with the title Herukābhidhānamahātantrarāja.  A 73 folio manuscript dated 1702.</note>
<note>Drepung Catalog, p. 672.</note>
<note>Hartzell, BST, pp. 110-112, with English translations of the 69 chapter titles.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmadhātukāyapādaśāstra.</title>
<note>EoB.  Exists only in Chinese translation.</note>
<note>Banerjee, SL, pp. 54, 64 65.  Said to be by Pūrṇa.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmadīpa.</title>
<note>See also Abhidharmapradīpa.</note>
<note>Padmanabh S. Jaini, A Rare Manuscript of Abhidharmadīpavibhāṣaprabhāvṛtti, contained in:  Bhāratī: Bulletin of the College of Indology [Banaras Hindu University], vol. 1, no. 1 (1956 57), pp. 50 56.</note>
<note>Padmanabh S. Jaini, Abhidharmadīpa with Vibhāṣāprabhāvṛtti: Critically Edited with Notes and Introduction, Kashi Prasad Jayaswal Research Institute (Patna 1959), with 144 pages in English, 499 pages in Sanskrit.  Reviewed by Alex Wayman in Journal of the American Oriental Society, vol. 82, no. 4 (October 1962), pp. 589 591.  According to Wayman, Jaini conjectures that the author of both works ought to be a follower of Saṅghabhadra, perhaps one named Vimalamitra (dated to between 450 and 550 or perhaps earlier).  It seeks to noteute Vasubandhu's Abhidharma work.  The author does noteer to himself in the Vṛtti with the name Dīpakāra (a name which seems to mean simply that he is the author of the Dīpa, meaning the Abhidharmadīpa, and thenoteore not a proper name).  Reviewed by J.W. de Jong in Indo Iranian Journal, vol. 6 (1962), pp. 173 175.</note>
<note>Padmanabh S. Jaini, On the Theory of Two Vasubandhus, Bulletin of the School of Oriental and African Studies, vol. 21, no. 1 3 (1958), pp. 48 53, at p. 49, says that the manuscript of this work was found together with its commentary, the Vibhāṣāprabhāvṛtti, in 1937, by Sānkṛtyāyana.</note>
<note>J.W. de Jong, L'auteur de l'Abhidharmadīpa, T'oung Pao, vol. 52 (1966), pp. 305 307.</note>
<note>Nakamura, p. 112.  Says it is by Dīpakāra, a disciple of Saṅghabhadra.</note>
<note>EoB discusses the manuscript found in Tibet by Saṅkṛtyāyana in 1937.  Jaini thinks that the person noteerred to as Dīpakāra ('author of the Dīpa') might have been Saṅghabhadra or a student of his (perhaps Vimalamitra), who was opposed to the Mahāyāna and to Vasubandhu, and thenoteore, it is said, fell to the deepest hell.</note>
<note>Its commentary, the Abhidharmapradīpavibhāṣāprabhadaṃvṛtti.  KCDS, p. 73.  A palmleaf Sanskrit manuscript now belonging to the Potala.</note>
<note>Bandurski, pp. 51 (catalogue no. 20) and 111.  The manuscript bears a cursive Tibetan title: Chos mngon pa'i sgron ma [illegible syllables follow].</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmahṛdayaśāstra.</title>
<note>Nakamura, p. 108.</note>
<note>EoB.  Probably the work by Dharmaśreṣṭhin, q.v.</note>
<note>Banerjee, SL, p. 74.  Attributed to Dharmajina (?), it exists in Chinese only.  Translated by Saṅghadeva in 391 CE, it contains 10 chapters.  It has a 10 chapter commentary with the same title, translated by Narendrayaśas in 563 CE.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmajñānakāyapādaśāstra.</title>
<note>Nakamura, p. 106.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmajñānaprasthānaśāstra.</title>
<note>EoB.  See EoB also under "Abhidharmāṣṭagrantha."</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmakośasamayapradīpikā.</title>
<note>Nakamura, p. 112.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmāmṛta.</title>
<note>Nakamura, p. 175.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmāmṛtaśāstra.</title>
<note>Nakamura, p. 108.</note>
<note>EoB under "Abhidharmāmṛta[rasa]śāstra."</note>
<note>Banerjee, SL, p. 74.  Attributed to Ghoṣa, it exists only in Chinese.  Contains 16 chapters.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmanyāyānusāra.</title>
<note>Nakamura, p. 112.  Says it is by Saṅghabhadra, alias Sahantabhadra.</note>
<note>EoB, says it is by Saṅghabhadra, contemporary of Vasubandhu, against whom he argues.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmapañcadharmacarita Sūtra.</title>
<note>EoB.  2nd century translation into Chinese by An Shigao, the author is unknown.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmapradīpa.</title>
<note>See also Abhidharmadīpa.</note>
<note>A Sanskrit manuscript, of unknown authorship, found at Zhwa lu Monastery.  SERS, p. 112.</note>
<note>Dge 'dun chos 'phel, Works (1990), vol. 1, p. 20 lists a slightly incomplete (70 folio) Indian manuscript at Zha lu, translating the title as Chos mngon sgron me bye brag tu gsal bar phye ba'i 'grel pa (this commentary contains the root text called the Abhidharmapradīpa).</note>
<note>Altekar, SLT, p. 59.  A metrical work of unknown authorship, the Sanskrit of both the main text and the commentary preserved in a fragmentary form in Tibet.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmaprajñaptipādaśāstra.</title>
<note>Nakamura, p. 106.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmaprakaraṇapādaśāstra.</title>
<note>Nakamura, p. 106.</note>
<note>Swati Ganguly, Analytical Study of the A pi da mo pinlei zu Lun (Abhidharmaprakaraṇapādaśāstra), Indian International Journal of Buddhist Studies, vol. 3 (2002), pp. 71 87.</note>
<note>Nakamura, p. 125 (Prakaraṇapāda).</note>
<note>EoB.</note>
<note>Jiryo Masuda, Origin and Doctrine of Early Indian Buddhist Schools, Asia Major, vol. 2 (1925), pp. 5 78, at p. 7.</note>
<note>Banerjee, SL, pp. 54, 62 64.  Said to have been composed by Sthavira Vasumitra at Puṣkaravatī Monastery.  There were two Chinese translations, the first by Guṇabhadra and Bodhiyaśas (in 435 443 CE), the other by Hsuan tsang (Xuanzang) in 659 CE.</note>
<note>Taishô nos. 1542 (translated by Guṇabhadra, Bodhiyaśas), 1542 (translated by Xuanzang).  Attributed to Vasumitra.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmaprakāśasādhanaśāstra.</title>
<note>EoB.  Said to be by, or translated by, Īśvara.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmasāra.</title>
<note>Liebenthal, Biography, p. 286.  Most authors Sanskritize the same text as Abhidharmahṛdaya, which has the same meaning.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmāṣṭagrantha.</title>
<note>Banerjee, SL, p. 54.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>T3436</rkts>
<title>Abhidharmāvatāraprakaraṇa</title>
<note>Rab tu byed pa chos mngon pa la 'jug pa.  Tôh. no. 4098. Dergé Tanjur, vol. NYU, folios 302r.7 323r.7.</note>
<note>Dergé colophon:  rab tu byed pa chos mngon pa la 'jug pa zhes bya ba rdzogs so.</note>
<note>M. van Velthem, Le Traité de la descente dans la profonde loi (Abhidharmāvatāraśāstra) de l'Arhat Skandhila (Louvain la Neuve 1977).  Reviewed by J.W. de Jong in T'oung Pao, vol. 65 (1979), pp. 294 303.</note>
<note>Nakamura, p. 112.</note>
<note>EoB under "Abhidharmāvatāraśāstra."</note>
<note>Banerjee, SL, p. 74.</note>
<note>Banerjee, ATT, pp. 376 377.  It exists in Chinese, but there the title is re Sanskritized as Abhidharmāvatāraśāstra.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmavibhāṣā Śāstra.</title>
<note>Banerjee, SL, pp. 10, 71.  Commentary on the Jñānaprasthānaśāstra.  It is attributed to Kātyāyanīputra.  Preserved in Chinese language only.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhidharmavijñānakāyapāda.</title>
<note>EoB.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhimantraphalasiddhidāyanī Vajrayoginīnairātmyaguhyeśvarī Mantradhāraṇī.</title>
<note>Matsunami, p. 287.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K301</rkts>
<title>Abhiniṣkramaṇa Sūtra</title>
<note>Mngon par 'byung ba'i mdo.  Tôh. no. 301.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. SA [72], folios 1v.1 125r.7.  Tr. by Dharmaśrībhadra and Rin chen bzang po.</note>
<note>Samuel Beal, The Romantic Legend of Śākya Buddha: A Translation of the Chinese Version of the Abhiniṣkramaṇasūtra (London 1875).  It was translated into Chinese by Jñānagupta ("Djnanakuta") in 587 592 CE, although its relationship to an Indic text and to the Tibetan translation is quite problematic.  Lin, Pudding, p. 94, says the Tibetan and Chinese translations are of two different texts, the Abhiniśkramṇa only existing in its Tibetan translation.</note>
<note>Joel Tatelman, The Trials of Yaśodharā: The Legend of the Buddha's Wife in the Bhadrakalpāvadāna, Buddhist Literature, vol. 1 (1999), pp. 176 261, at pp. 182, 188, gives the untypical information that Beal's book is a translation of a very hypothetical Sanskrit title *Śākyamunibuddhacarita, and that it exists only in the form of the Chinese text Fo pên hsing chi ching (Taishô 190).</note>
<note>Brief studies of some aspects of the text have been published by Yuko Matsuda (Kyoto University), evidently only in Japanese.</note>
<note>Matsuda Yûko, Chinese Versions of the Buddha's Biography, Indogaku Bukkyôgaku Kenkyû, vol. 37, no. 1 (1988), pp. 489 480.</note>
<note>Hubert Durt, The Pregnancy of Māyā: 3. Late Episodes, a Few More Words on the Textual Sources, Journal of the International College for Advanced Buddhist Studies, vol. 7  (March 2004), pp. 55 72, at p. 56.</note>
<note>EoB.  Not preserved in Sanskrit.  The Chinese version has 60 chapters (which brings to my mind the Sixty Deeds of Lord Shenrab...).</note>
<note>Dasgupta, ORC, p. 25 (Abhiniśramaṇa Sūtra).</note>
<note>Best, Paekche, p. 188 (Abiniṣkramaṇa sūtra).  Translated into Chinese by Jñānagupta in 587 CE.</note>
<note>Davidson, KCN, p. 70.</note>
<note>The Chinese text has more to do with the Lalitavistara, and doesn't much resemble the Tibetan text with the 'same' title.  Luczanits, Prior1.  From what I have seen, this statement is accurate.  There •are• close parallels, but with episodes coming in a different order, and sometimes leaning more toward their Lalitavistara versions.</note>
<note>Franklin, Life, p. 946.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ābhiprāyikārthagāthā.</title>
<note>Bandurski, p. 63.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhisamācārikadharma.</title>
<note>A Vinaya text belonging to the Lokottaravādins.</note>
<note>Ryôshû Kouda, Abhisamācārika Dharma, Chapter 7, Annual of the Sanko Research Institute for the Studies of Buddhism, vol. 36 (2005), pp. 15 43, an annotated Japanese translation.</note>
<note>Giulio Agostini, On the Nikāya Affiliation of the Śrīghanācārasaṅgraha and the Sphuṭārthā Śrīghanācārasaṅgrahaṭīkā, Journal of the International Association of Buddhist Studies, vol. 26, no. 1 (2003), pp. 97 114, at p. 104 ff.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>T339</rkts>
<title>Abhisamayakrama</title>
<note>(Mngon par rtogs pa'i rim pa).  Tôh. no. 1209.  Dergé Tanjur, vol. JA, folios 309r.6 311v.1.  Tr. by Ratnavajra and Shākya ye shes.</note>
<note>EoB.</note>
<note>A text by this title (a Hevajra work) is listed in Bandurski, p. 76 (no. 20 in the list).</note>
<note>Black Hat Tanjur, p. 459.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhisambodhikrama.</title>
<note>Dge 'dun chos 'phel, Works (1990), vol. 1, p. 22 lists an Indian manuscript at Zha lu.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K564</rkts>
<title>Abhiṣecanī-nāma-dhāraṇī</title>
<note>('Phags pa dbang bskur ba zhes bya ba'i gzungs).  Tôh. no. 569 (also, no. 859).  Dergé Kanjur, vol. PHA, folios 195r.6 196v.4.  Tr. by Jinamitra, Dānaśīla and Ye shes sde.</note>
<note>EoB.  Also listed there under "Abhiṣiñcanī-nāma-dhāraṇī."</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>*Abhiṣekarāja</title>
<note>(Dbang bskur rgyal po)</note>
<note>Rhoton, CD, p. 196.  A spurious scripture among the 'New Translations.'</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhiṣekasādhanoddeśa.</title>
<note>KCDS, p. 152.  Sanskrit palmleaf manuscript now belonging to the Potala, formerly from Ngor Monastery.  The Tibetan titles given here are:  Dbang bskur sgrub thabs kyi gsal bshad and Dbang mdor bstan gyi rgyud.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhiṣekavidhāna.</title>
<note>BSM, p. 10 (MBB II 16).  A 31 folio manuscript.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abhiṣekavidhi.</title>
<note>EoB.  Exists in Sanskrit in the form of a manuscript dated 1440.  On entering the maṇḍala.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Abitaki.</title>
<note>O. Sertkaya + K. Roehrborn, Bruchstücke der alttürkischen Amitabha Literatur aus Istanbul, Ural Altaische Jahrbuch, vol. 4 (1984), pp. 97 117.</note>
<note>Geng Shimin, Study of Two Folios of the Uighur Text "Abitaki,"  Acta Orientalia Hungarica, vol. 57, no. 1 (2004), pp. 105 113.  Although the title (which isn't actually a title) has to be Sanskritized as Amitābha Sūtra, its content has nothing to do with the text by that name.  It is a Pure Land (Sukhāvatī) text, and promises rebirth in the Pure Land by chanting the name of Amitābha Buddha if only once.</note>
<note>Geng Shimin, Study of Another Two Folios of the Uighur Text Abitaki, Acta Orientalia Hungarica, vol. 59, no. 1 (March 2006), pp. 47 56.</note>
<note>A. Temir, K. Kudara + K. Roehrborn, Die alttürkischen Abitaki Fragmente des Etnografya Müzesi, Ankara, Turcica, vol. 16 (1984).</note>
<note>Klimkeit, BTCA, p. 62.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Acalābhiṣekavidhi.</title>
<note>BSM, p. 4 (MBB I 69).  A 36 folio manuscript.</note>
<note>Probably the same as the text listed under the title Pañcābhiṣeka Acalābhiṣeka in BSM, p. 27 (CSG 10), a 36 folio manuscript.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Acalacakra</title>
<note>(Mi g.yo ba'i 'khor lo).  Tr. by Chos kyi rdo rje and Nam mkha' rdo rje.</note>
<note>EoB.  Evidently not to be found in Dergé Tanjur.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Acalahṛdaya.</title>
<note>Matsunami, p. 287.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K432</rkts>
<title>Acalakalpa tantrarāja</title>
<note>('Phags pa mi g.yo ba'i rtog pa'i rgyud kyi rgyal po).  Tôh. no. 434.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. CA, folios 1v.1 12r.7.  Tr. by Athuladāsavajra and Mar pa Chos kyi dbang phyug grags pa.</note>
<note>EoB.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K434</rkts>
<title>Acalamahāguhyatantra</title>
<note>('Phags pa mi g.yo ba'i gsang rgyud chen po).  Tôh. no. 434.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. CA, folios 14v.4 16v.5.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Acalamahākrodharājasya sarvatathāgatasya balāparimitavīravinayasvākhyāta-nāma-kalpa</title>
<note>(De bzhin gshegs pa thams cad kyi khro bo'i rgyal po 'phags pa mi g.yo ba de'i stobs dpag tu med pa rtul phod pa 'dul bar gsungs pa zhes bya ba'i rtog pa).  Tôh. no. 495.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. THA, folios 261v.1 322r.7.  Tr. by Ulaśamarakṣita and Glan Dar ma blo gros.  Revised by Chos skyong bzang po.  Revised again by Ānandamaṅgala.</note>
<note>Evidently this is the text edited in J. Oshika, ed., Tibetan Text of Ārya Acala Mahākrodharāja Kalpa, Acta Indologica, vol. 4 (1978).</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K625</rkts>
<title>Acala-nāma-dhāraṇī</title>
<note>('Phags pa mi g.yo ba zhes bya ba'i gzungs).  Tôh. no. 631 (also, no. 963).  Dergé Kanjur, vol. BA, folios 68r.3 80v.7.  Tr. by Dharmaśrīmitra (but read Dharmatāśīla in Tôh. no. 963) and Chos kyi bzang po.</note>
<note>EoB.</note>
<note>Shorei Nakayama, [Japanese Translation of the Tibetan Text of the Ārya-acala-nāma-dhāraṇī; 'Phags pa khro bo mi g.yo ba'i gzungs], Journal of the Naritasan Institute of Buddhist Studies, vol. 35 (2012), pp. 47-67.  Includes transcription of the Tibetan text.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Acalasādhana.</title>
<note>Matsunami, pp. 247, 287.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ācāraṅgasūtra.</title>
<note>Jaina scripture.  EoB, vol. 6, p. 511.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ācāryābhiṣekavidhi.</title>
<note>KCDS, p. 139.  Palmleaf Sanskrit manuscript now belonging to the Potala.  </note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ācāryaparīkṣā.</title>
<note>Two brief citations from a Sanskrit text by this title are reproduced in Lal, Lupta, vol. 2, p. 4.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Acchariyabbhutadhammasutta.</title>
<note>Luczanits, Prior1.</note>
<note>Bareau, Jeunesse, p. 201 et passim.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K79</rkts>
<title>Acintyabuddhaviṣayanirdeśa-nāma-mahāyānasūtra</title>
<note>('Phags pa sangs rgyas kyi yul bsam gyis mi khyab pa bstan pa zhes bya ba theg pa chen po'i mdo).  Tôh. no. 79.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. CA, folios 266v.6 284v.7.  Tr. by Jinamitra, Dānaśīla, Munivarman and Ye shes sde.</note>
<note>Nakamura, p. 179.</note>
<note>EoB.  Chinese versions exist.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K103</rkts>
<title>Acintyaprabhānirdeśa-nāma-dharmaparyāya</title>
<note>('Phags pa khye'u snang ba bsam gyis mi khyab pas bstan pa zhes bya ba'i chos kyi rnam grangs).  Tôh. no. 103.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. NGA, folios 275r.1 285v.4.  Tr. by Jinamitra, Dānaśīla and Ye shes sde.</note>
<note>EoB under "Acintyaprabhāsabodhisattvanirdeśa."  The Peking Tanjur has the same text with the title Khye'u snang ba bsam gyis mi khyab pas bstan pa zhes bya ba'i chos kyi rnam grangs, and says it was tr. by Surendrabodhi and Ye shes sde.  A Chinese translation by Kumārajīva exists.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K268</rkts>
<title>Acintyarājasūtra-nāma-mahāyānasūtra</title>
<note>('Phags pa bsam gyis mi khyab pa'i rgyal po).  Tôh. no. 268.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. YA, folios 5v.3 7r.2.</note>
<note>EoB lists Chinese versions.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K319</rkts>
<title>Adbhutadharmaparyāya</title>
<note>('Phags pa rmad du byung ba zhes bya ba'i chos kyi rnam grangs).  Tôh. no. 319.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. SA, folios 194r.1 196v.7.  Tr. by Jinamitra, Surendrabodhi and Ye shes sde.</note>
<note>Yael Bentor, The Redactions of the Adbhutadharmaparyāya  from Gilgit," Journal of the International Association of Buddhist Studies, vol. 11, no. 2 (1988), pp. 21 52.</note>
<note>Yael Bentor, Miniature Stūpas, Images and Relics: The Sanskrit Manuscripts of the Adbhutadharmaparyāya from Gilgit and its Tibetan Translation, Master's thesis, Indiana University (Bloomington 1987).  Only some parts of this were published in the just mentioned article.</note>
<note>EoB lists the three Chinese translations.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Adbhutahetuparyāya Sūtra.</title>
<note>EoB.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Āddhātakauṇḍinyajātakāvadāna.</title>
<note>A chapter in the Sambhadrāvadānamālā.  Matsunami, p. 236.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Adhikaraṇavastu</title>
<note>(Rtsod pa'i gzhi).  16th section of the Vinayavastu.</note>
<note>EoB.</note>
<note>R. Gnoli, The Gilgit Manuscript of the Śayanāsanavastu and Adhikaraṇavastu, Serie Orientale Roma no. 50 (Rome 1978).</note>
<note>Panglung, EMV, pp. 82-83.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>T3608</rkts>
<title>Adhikārasaṅgraha</title>
<note>(Spyir btang ba yang dag par bsdus pa).  Tr. by Blo gros brtan pa.  Tôh. no. 4273.  Dergé Tanjur, vol. RE, folios 38v.7 46r.6.</note>
<note>Dergé colophon: bal po'i mthil ye rang gi grong khyer du dge slong dpal ldan blo gros brtan pas dag par bsgyur ba'o.</note>
<note>Diemberger, White Crystal, p. 66, says it was translated by Dpang Lo.</note>
<note>EoB says it was translated by Dpang Blo gros brtan pa at Ye rang gi grong khyer [Lalitpur, in Nepal Valley].</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ādibuddhagīta.</title>
<note>Matsunami, p. 287.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ādikarmapradīpa.</title>
<note>See under Anupamavajra.</note>
<note>Nakamura, p. 332.</note>
<note>EoB.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ādityadvādaśa.</title>
<note>Matsunami, p. 288.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ādityadvādaśasūryadhāraṇī.</title>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Adhyardhaśatikāprajñāpāramitā.</title>
<note>Ian Astley Kristensen, The Rishukyô: The Sino Japanese Tantric Prajñāpāramitā in 150 Verses, Institute of Buddhist Studies (Tring 1991).</note>
<note>J.W. de Jong, Notes on the Sources and the Text of the Sang Hyang Kamahāyānan Mantranaya, Bijdragen tot de taal , land  en volkenkunde, vol. 130 (1974), pp. 465 482.  The Tibetan version has a title corresponding to  Śrīparamādyamantrakalpakhaṇḍa (Tôh. no. 488), q.v.</note>
<note>E. Leumann, Die Nordarischen Abschnitte der Adhyardhaśatikā Prajñāpāramitā, Text und Übersetzung mit Glossar, contained in: Journal of the Taisho University vols. 6 7 [In Commemoration of the Sixtieth Birthday of Professor Unrai Wogihara, Part II, European Section], Taisho University (Sugamo, Tokyo 1930), pp. 47 88.</note>
<note>Himansu Bhusan Sarkar, The Philosophical Matrix and Content of the Vajrayāna System as Practiced by the Śailendra Rulers of Central Java (c. 775 856 A.D.): A Search for Its Origin (A Literary and Inscriptional Approach), Annals of the Bhandarkar Oriental Research Institute, vols. 58 59 (1977 78), pp. 921 938 at p. 929 ff.</note>
<note>Toru Tomabechi, ed., The Adhyardhaśatikā Prajñāpāramitā: Sanskrit + Tibetan Texts Critically Edited, Sanskrit Texts from the Tibetan Autonomous Region series no. 5, Österreichischen Akademie der Wissenschaften (Vienna 2009).</note>
<note>Davidson, IEB, pp. 146, 152.</note>
<note>Hoernle, MRBL, p. 389.</note>
<note>Nakamura, pp. 161 (also called Śatapañcāśatikā), 329.</note>
<note>EoB under "Ardhyardhaśataka."  Here the naming problem is discussed, with a detailed outline and bibliography.  It corresponds to the Tibetan text entitled 'Phags pa shes rab kyi pha rol tu phyin pa'i tshul brgya lnga bcu pa (Tôh. no. 489).</note>
<note>Woodward, EBSA, p. 339.  He says this is also known as the Naya Sūtra.</note>
<note>R.E. Emmerick made an entry on this text in E. Yarshater, ed., Encyclopaedia Iranica (London 1985), vol. 1, p. 456.</note>
<note>KCDS, p. 5.  Palmleaf manuscript now belonging to the Nor bu gling ka. Title given as Adhyardhaśatikābhagavatīprajñāpāramitā.  Number of folios not stated.</note>
<note>EoB, vol. 5, pp. 552 553, 554.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K69</rkts>
<title>Adhyāśayasañcodana-nāma-mahāyānasūtra</title>
<note>('Phags pa lhag pa'i bsam pa bskul ba zhes bya ba theg pa chen po'i mdo).  Tôh. no. 69.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. CA, folios 131r.7 153v.7.  Tr. by Jinamitra, Surendrabodhi and Ye shes sde.</note>
<note>David Snellgrove, Note on the Adhyāśayasaṃcodana Sūtra, Bulletin of the School of Oriental and African Studies, vol. 21 (1958), pp. 620 623.</note>
<note>Davidson, IEB, p. 103.</note>
<note>Kapstein, PLBT, p. 29.</note>
<note>Nakamura, p. 180.</note>
<note>EoB under "Adyāśayasañcodana."</note>
<note>Tauscher, Gondhla, p. 100 (no. 42): Lhag pa'i bsam pas bskul ba'i mdo.</note>
<note>See Silk, Managing, p. 19.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Adhyātmasādhanopāyikā.</title>
<note>A brief citation from a text by this title is reproduced in Lal, Lupta, vol. 2, p. 1.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ādibuddha.</title>
<note>Ten brief citations from a Sanskrit text by this title are reproduced in Lal, Lupta, vol. 2, pp. 4 7.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ādibuddhadhāraṇī.</title>
<note>Günter Grönbold, Weitere Ādibuddha-Texte, Wiener Zeitschrift für die Kunde Südasiens, vol. 39 (1995), pp. 45-60.  Has Sanskrit text and German translation.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ādibuddhamahāyānatantra.</title>
<note>Dhīḥ: Journal of the Rare Buddhist Texts Research Unit, vol. 45 (2008), pp. 5 8.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ādibuddhasya Mahimaślokāḥ.</title>
<note>Günter Grönbold, Weitere Ādibuddha-Texte, Wiener Zeitschrift für die Kunde Südasiens, vol. 39 (1995), pp. 45-60.  Has Sanskrit text and German translation.</note>
 </item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ādiyogasamādhi.</title>
<note>Matsunami, pp. 247 248.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K452</rkts>
<title>Advayasamatāvijayākhyā kalpamahārāja</title>
<note>('Phags pa gnyis su med pa mnyam pa nyid rnam par rgyal ba zhes bya ba'i rtog pa'i rgyal po chen po).  Tôh. no. 452.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. CHA, folios 58v.3 103r.3. Tr. by Bu ston Rin chen grub.  Revised by Mi bzang Mgon po'i skyabs.</note>
<note>Stog Palace Kanjur colophon (no. 414): mkhan chen thar pa lo tsā ba'i phyag dpe'i gseb nas shog yar lnga byung ba sngar bsgyur las phyis nyang stod smad 'gro'i gtsug lag khang nas rgya dpe lhag ma rnams rnyed nas bsgyur bar rtsom pa na / dpal dus kyi 'khor lo'i phyi nang gzhan gsum gyi tshul la mi 'jigs pa'i spobs pa thob pa'i bla ma yang dag pa'i dge ba'i bshes gnyen chen po / legs par sbyar ba'i skad kyi brda sprod pa'i tshul la blo gros shin tu byang ba'i 'jig rten gyi mig chos grags dpal bzang po'i bkas bskul zhing sbyin bdag mdzad nas / bu ston gyis bsgyur ba'i yi ge pa ni dge slong rin chen rgyal mtshan no //  rgyud min rgyud ltar bcos pa yis / chos min sun dbyung bya phyir dang dam tshig snang ba spol ba'i phyir / ji ltar nus bzhin bsgyur ba lags / 'di don 'byed pa'i 'grel pa dang rgya dpe'i dpe dbang ma rnyed cing don zab sgra ni rtogs dka' la / saṃ skri ta la ma byang bas / sgra don ji bzhin ma 'byor pa'i nongs de mkhas rnams bzod mdzad cing / phyis 'byung skad gnyis smra rnams kyis / ma dag shes na bcos par zhu / rgyud chen 'di ni bsgyur ba las / dge ba bdag gis gang thob pa / de yis mtha' yas 'gro ba kun rdo rje 'chang chen nyid gyur cig.  </note>
<note>EoB.</note>
<note>Scripture cited in Kyobpa Jigten Sumgon, Introduction to Mahamudra, the Co emergent Unification, text with English translation by Khenpo Konchok Tamphel, Songtsen (Dehra Dun 2004), pp. 28 31, with the shortened title Gnyis med rnam rgyal.</note>
<note>A work entitled Gnyis med rnam rgyal, which could mean this text (?), is said to be a spurious scripture, composed in Tibet.  Rhoton, CD, p. 196.</note>
<note>Dge 'dun chos 'phel, Works (1990), vol. 1, p. 26, lists an Indian manuscript at Zha lu:  'Phags pa gnyis su med par mnyam pa nyid rnam par rgyal ba'i rtogs pa, in 22 chapters.  The author believes this was a personal copy belonging to Thar pa Lo tsā ba.</note>
<note>Sde srid, Mchod sdong, p. 435, quoting Bu ston, I believe, lists this among works that should not be included in the Kanjur (although they evidently had been included there at some time).  But he is evidently talking about an older translation, done by Chos kyi blo gros (Mar pa?), which had been corrupted by interpolations added by a Tibetan, according to Chag Chos rje dpal and others.  There is another smaller version of the Gnyis med rnam rgyal, which is 'authentic' (yang dag), but it is said to have been made by Rgya Pho ba lung pa.  Some say that it was an autotranslation by Smṛti, but this needs to be checked.    But the Sde srid adds that it is not only to be found in the tables of contents of the Tshal pa Bka' 'gyur and the Snar thang, but in the Tantra section, vol. CA, of the Rgyal rtse Them spang ma, is a 22-chapter work with this title.  Bu ston himself found the authentic Indian texts and translated it (this discussion goes on and on).</note>
<note>In fact, in Lal, Lupta, vol. 2, p. 1, is a quoted passage from the Sanskrit text.  But note that here the title is given as Advayasamatāvijayamahāyogatantra.</note>
<note>Willemen, Defining, p. 18.</note>
<note>Ms. Fan Muyou, a Ph.D. student in Peking University, is currently (2006) working on a study of this text, which also exists in a Chinese translation.  This information was found on the internet, in the form of an abstract, as a downloadable PDF.</note>
<note>Fan Mayou, Some Notes on Editing the Sanskrit Manuscript of the Advayasamatāvijayamahākalparajā on the Basis of the Chinese and Tibetan Translations, Tantric Studies, vol. 1 (2008), pp. 155-180.</note>
<note>Fan Mayou, Some Remarks on the Relationship between a Sanskrit Manuscript of the Advayasamatāvijaya from Tibet and Its Tibetan Translation, Annual Report of the International Research Institute for Advanced Buddhology at Soka University (for the Academic Year 2007), vol. 11 (2008), pp. 375 380.</note>
<note>Fan Muyou, Some Grammatical Notes on the Advayasamatāvijaya-mahākalparāja, contained in: Ernst Steinkellner, ed., with Duan Qing + Helmut Krasser, Sanskrit Manuscripts in China: Proceedings of a Panel at the 2008 Beijing Seminar on Tibetan Studies, October 13 to 17, China Tibetology Publishing House (Beijing 2009), pp. 41-46.</note>
<note>Fan Muyou, The Trilingual Version of the Manuscript Advayasamatāvijayamahākalparājā Previously Preserved as Number 76 in the China Ethnic Library and Relevant Research.  A PDF downloaded from the internet.</note>
<note>Eimer, TKPC, p. 53.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Advayaśatikāprajñāpāramitā.</title>
<note>Matsunami, p. 187.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Agajakumārasya Prabhāsavirajaḥ samucchrayagandheśvararāja tathāgatavyākaraṇa.</title>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Āgamasiddhikārikā.</title>
<note>See Bandurski, p. 37.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Agastya Jātaka.</title>
<note>Part seven of Jātakamālā of Āryaśūra.  Matsunami, p. 228.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ageyanāvikapravrajyāvratacaraṇaparivarta.</title>
<note>A chapter in the Sambhadrāvadānamālā.  Matsunami, p. 236.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Aggañña Sutta.</title>
<note>EoB.</note>
<note>Nattier, OUFT, pp. 11 13.</note>
<note>Steven Collins, A Discourse on What is Primary: An Annotated Translation, Journal of Indian Philosophy, vol. 21 (1993), pp. 301 393.</note>
<note>Richard Gombrich, The Buddha's Book of Genesis?  Indo Iranian Journal, vol. 35 (1992), pp. 159 178.</note>
<note>Alf Hiltebeitel, Recontextualizing Satire of Brahmanical Dharmaśāstra in the Aggañña Sutta, paper given at the 2008 IABS conference in Atlanta.</note>
<note>Konrad Meisig, Das Sūtra von den vier Ständen.  Das Aggañña Sutta im Licht seiner chinesischen Parallelen von Konrad Meisig, Otto Harrassowitz (Wiesbaden 1988).</note>
<note>Ulrich Schneider, Ein Beitrag zur Textgeschichte des Aggañña Suttanta, Indo Iranian Journal, vol. 1 (1957), pp. 253 285.</note>
<note>Ernst Waldschmidt, Fragment of a Buddhist Sanskrit Text on Cosmogony, contained in:  J. Tilakasiri, ed., Añjali: Papers on Indology and Buddhism (Wijesekera Felicitation) University of Ceylon (Peradeniya 1970), pp. 40 45.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Aggavaṃsa.</title>
<note>Nakamura, pp. 24, 120.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K407</rkts>
<title>Agnimālā tantrarāja</title>
<note>(Dpal me'i phreng ba'i rgyud kyi rgyal po).  Tôh. no. 407.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. GA, folios 244v.1 245v.6.  Tr. by Gayadhara and Shākya ye shes.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K1097</rkts>
<title>Agracaryāpraṇidhāna</title>
<note>(Mchog gi spyod pa'i smon lam).  Tôh. no. 1097.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. WAM, folios 267r.5 268v.1.  Tr. by Prajñāvara and Ye shes sde.</note>
<note>EoB.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Agraprajñapti.</title>
<note>NTSH, p. 178.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K527</rkts>
<title>Agrapradīpadhāraṇī vidyārāja</title>
<note>('Phags pa rigs sngags kyi rgyal po sgron ma mchog gi gzungs).  Tôh. no. 528 (also, no. 858).  Dergé Kanjur, vol. NA, folios 85v.1 90v.3.</note>
<note>EoB, with list of Chinese translations.</note>
<note>Huaiyu Chen, Newly Identified Khotanese Fragments in the British Library and Their Chinese Parallels, Journal of the Royal Asiatic Society, series 3, vol. 22, no. 2 (2012), pp. 265-279.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K736</rkts>
<title>Agravidyāmantra</title>
<note>(Mchog thob pa'i rig sngags).  Tôh. no. 742 (also, no. 1036).  Dergé Kanjur, vol. TSHA, folios 235v.5 236r.3.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ahorātrapadasādhanacarcā.</title>
<note>BSM, p. 15 (MBB II 119).  A 23 folio manuscript.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ahorātravratacaityasevānuśaṃsāvadāna.</title>
<note>Ratna Handurukande, Three Sanskrit Texts on Caitya Worship in Relation to Ahorātravrata, International Institute for Buddhist Studies (Tokyo 2000).  Also contains two texts, one in verse the other in prose, entitled Ahorātravratakathā.  Reviewed by Christian Wedemeyer in Journal of the Royal Asiatic Society.</note>
<note>Matsunami, pp. 213, 233 (Ahorātravratakathā).</note>
<note>BSM, p. 9 (MBB II 3).  Ahorātravratakathā.  A manuscript in 17 folios dated 1849.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ajanyakali-nāma-dhāraṇī.</title>
<note>Matsunami, p. 288.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K216</rkts>
<title>Ajātaśatrukaukṛttyavinodana-nāma-mahāyānasūtra</title>
<note>('Phags pa ma skyes dgra'i 'gyod pa bsal ba zhes bya ba theg pa chen po'i mdo).  Tôh. no. 216.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. TSHA, folios 211v.2 268v.7.  Tr. by Mañjuśrīgarbha and Ratnarakṣita.</note>
<note>EoB.</note>
<note>It seems to be directly quoted in another sūtra, which is quite an unusual thing to happen.  Paul Harrison, Druma kinnara rāja paripṛcchā sūtra, International Institute for Buddhist Studies (Tokyo 1992), p. xvi.</note>
<note>Paul Harrison and Jens Uwe Hartmann, Ajātaśatrukaukṛtyavinodanasūtra, contained in: Jens Braarvig, ed., Manuscripts in the Schöyen Collection I: Buddhist Manuscripts Volume One, Hermes Publishing (Oslo 2000), pp. 167 216.</note>
<note>Jens Uwe Hartmann and Paul Harrison, A Sanskrit Fragment of the Ajātaśatru kaukṛtya vinodanā sūtra, contained in: Paul Harrison and G. Schopen, eds., Sūryacandrāya: Essays in Honour of Akira Yuyama (Swisttal Odendorf 1998), pp. 67 86.</note>
<note>Jens Uwe Hartmann and Paul Harrison, Another Fragment of the Ajātaśatrukaukṛtyavinodanasūtra, contained in: Jens Braarvig, Paul Harrison, Jens Uwe Hartmann, Kazunobu Matsuda, Lore Sander, ed., Buddhist Manuscripts in the Schøyen Collection, Volume Two (Hermes Academic Publishing (Oslo 2002), pp. 45 50.</note>
<note>Tenshô Miyazaki, Discerning the Original Language of the Tibetan Versions of Mahāyāna Sūtras: From a Simple Mistake in the Ldem kar ma Regarding the Ajātaśatrukaukṛtyavinodanāsūtra, Journal of Indian and Buddhist Studies, vol. 55, no. 3 (March 2007), pp. 1101 1105.  The Ldan dkar ma classifies it as a translation from Chinese, while the 'Phang thang ma (correctly) says it was translated from an Indian language.</note>
<note>Tauscher, Gondhla, p. 100 (no. 100): Rgyal po ma skyes sgra'i mdo.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ajātaśatruparidāpitāvadāna.</title>
<note>Matsunami, p. 231.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ajitasenavyākaraṇanirdeśa Sūtra.</title>
<note>A now available Sanskrit sūtra that was not translated into Tibetan.  Only a few other examples have been noticed.</note>
<note>Nakamura, p. 234.  "Seems to have been composed in Kashmir."</note>
<note>Dutt, Gilgit Manuscripts, vol. 1, pp. 101 136 (and English introduction, p. 73 ff.).</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Akālamaraṇanivāraṇopāya</title>
<note>(Dus ma yin par 'chi ba bzlog pa'i thabs).  Tanjur text found in Cordier catalogue, but apparently not in the Dergé.</note>
<note>EoB.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Akāretyādimantraṇaprapūjyāstevisarjjayet...</title>
<note>KCDS, p. 138.  Palmleaf Sanskrit manuscript now belonging to the Potala.  Evidently not a proper title, probably just the opening of an untitled text.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ākāśacakrayeṇamantra (??).</title>
<note>KCDS, p. 18.  Tibetan title given as Stong pa'i 'khor lo'i gzungs sngags (although Nam mkha' 'khor lo'i sngags would seem more apt).</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K260</rkts>
<title>Ākāśagarbha-nāma-mahāyānasūtra</title>
<note>('Phags pa nam mkha'i snying po zhes bya ba theg pa chen po'i mdo).  Tôh. no. 260.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. ZA, folios 264r.4 283v.2.  Tr. by Śākyaprabha and Ratnarakṣita.</note>
<note>Nakamura, p. 218.</note>
<note>EoB, with noteerences to Chinese translations.</note>
<note>Rhoton, CD, p. 235.</note>
<note>Denwood, Catalogue, no. 396.</note>
<note>This sūtra definitely must predate 5th century.  On an extended citation found in the Śikṣāsamuccaya, which includes a dream incubation type of practice, see Paul Harrison, Mediums and Messages: notelections on the Production of Mahāyāna Sūtras, Eastern Buddhist, n.s. vol. 35, nos. 1 2 (2003), pp. 115 151, at p. 140.</note>
<note>See Silk, Managing, p. 17, for a valuable set of noteerences.  This sūtra rejects official administrative roles "and even study" while emphasizing meditative practice.</note>
<note>An English translation has been posted at the "84000" website.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Akhbar a Sin wal Hind [News of China and India].</title>
<note>Some have attributed it to Suleyman the Merchant [Suleiman].  It was compiled in around 851 CE.  Raphael Israeli, Medieval Muslim Travelers to China, Journal of Muslim Minority Affairs, vol. 20, no. 2 (2000), pp. 313 321.</note>
<note>Has been edited and translated into French twice:  Jean Sauvager, Relation de la Chine et de l'Inde (Paris 1948).  M. Reinaud, Relation des Voyages en Chine et en Inde (Paris 1845).</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ākhyāta Nāmnita.</title>
<note>Evidently an incipit.  KCDS, p. 153.  Sanskrit palmleaf manuscript now belonging to the Potala, formerly from Ngor Monastery.  A note says it ought to be checked if this belongs to the cycle of the Kalāpa grammar.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K377</rkts>
<title>Ākhyātatantrottaravajravārāhyabhidhānād vārāhyabhibodhana</title>
<note>(Phag mo mngon par brjod pa bshad pa'i rgyud phyi ma las / phag mo mngon par byang chub pa).  Tôh. no. 377.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. GA, folios 52v.5 60r.7.  Tr. by Jñānākara and Khun ston Dngos grub.</note>
<note>Dergé colophon:  bshad pa'i rgyud phyi ma las phag mo mngon par byang chub pa zhes bya ba rdzogs so //  // rgya gar gyi mkhan po dznyā nā ka ra'i zhal snga nas dang / zhu chen gyi lo tsā ba khu ston dngos grub kyis bsgyur te gtan la phab pa.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>T1473</rkts>
<title>Akṣasūtralakṣaṇa</title>
<note>(Bzlas pa'i phreng ba'i mtshan nyid).  Tôh. no. 2650.  Dergé Tanjur, vol. JU, folios 299v.4 300r.6.  Tr. by Ratna and Shes rab rgyal mtshan.</note>
<note>EoB.  According to Cordier, translated by Parahita and Shes rab rgyal mtshan.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K175</rkts>
<title>Akṣayamatinirdeśa-nāma-mahāyānasūtra</title>
<note>('Phags pa blo gros mi zad pas bstan pa zhes bya ba theg pa chen po'i mdo).  Tôh. no. 175.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. MA, folios 79r.1 174v.7.  Tr. by Dharmatāśīla.</note>
<note>Jens Braarvig, Akṣayamatinirdeśasūtra, Solum Forlag (Oslo 1993), in 2 volumes.  Tibetan text edition, index, portions with Sanskrit reconstructions, and an English translation that is heavily annotated.  Reviewed by J.W. de Jong in Indo Iranian Journal, vol. 39 (1996), pp. 171 176.  Review by Ulrich Pagel in Bulletin of the School of Oriental and African Studies, vol. 58, no. 2 (1995), pp. 385 387.</note>
<note>Phillip A. Maas, A Phylogenetic Approach to the Transmission of the Tibetan Kanjur: The Akṣayamatinirdeśa Revisited, contained in: Vogel Festschrift, pp. 229 244.</note>
<note>Alex Wayman, The Samādhi Lists of the Akṣayamatinirdeśasūtra and the Mahāvyutpatti, Acta Orientalia Hungarica, vol. 34 (1980), pp. 305 318.</note>
<note>Alex Wayman, A Report on the Akṣayamatinirdeśasūtra, Studies in Indo Asian Art and Culture, vol. 6 (New Delhi 1980), pp. xx xx.</note>
<note>Scripture cited in Kyobpa Jigten Sumgon, Introduction to Mahāmudrā, the Co emergent Unification, text with English translation by Khenpo Konchok Tamphel, Songtsen (Dehra Dun 2004), pp. 38 39.</note>
<note>Nakamura, pp. 210, 240.</note>
<note>EoB.</note>
<note>Drepung Catalog, p. 893.</note>
<note>Tauscher, Gondhla, p. 101 (no. 68).</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K89</rkts>
<title>Akṣayamatiparipṛcchā-nāma-mahāyānasūtra</title>
<note>('Phags pa blo gros mi zad pas zhus pa zhes bya ba theg pa chen po'i mdo).  Tôh. no. 89.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. CHA, folios 175v.2 182v.6.  Tr. by Surendrabodhi and Ye shes sde.  Revised by Dharmatāśīla.</note>
<note>EoB.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K614</rkts>
<title>Akṣirogapraśamanisūtra</title>
<note>('Phags pa mig nad rab tu zhi bar byed pa'i mdo).  Tôh. no. 620 (also, no. 1018).  Dergé Kanjur, vol. BA, folios 60v.4 61r.1.</note>
<note>EoB.</note>
<note>Berthold Laufer, Verzeichnis der tibetischen Handschriften der Königlichen Bibliothek zu Dresden, Zeitschrift der Deutschen Morgenländischen Gesellschaft, vol. 55 (1901), p. 111 (nos. 66 70).</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Akṣobhyadhāraṇī.</title>
<note>Matsunami, p. 288.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Akṣobhyamaṇḍalakriyā.</title>
<note>BSM, p. 8 (MBB I 141).  A 35 folio manuscript.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Akṣobhyanāthasya sādhana.</title>
<note>Kazuhiro Kawasaki, On a Birch bark Sanskrit Manuscript Preserved in the Tibet Museum, Journal of Indian and Buddhist Studies, vol. 52, no. 2 (2004), pp. 903 905, at p. 51 (text no. 5).</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Akṣobhyamaṇḍalapūjāvidhi.</title>
<note>BSM, p. 5 (MBB I 87).  An 18 folio manuscript dated 1912 CE.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>T1477</rkts>
<title>Akṣobhyasādhana</title>
<note>(Mi 'khrugs pa'i sgrub thabs).  Tôh. no. 2658.  Dergé Tanjur, vol. JU, folios 310v.6 311r.7.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K50</rkts>
<title>Akṣobhyatathāgatasya vyūha-nāma-mahāyānasūtra</title>
<note>('Phags pa de bzhin gshegs pa mi 'khrugs pa'i bkod pa zhes bya ba theg pa chen po'i mdo).  Tôh. no. 50.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. KHA, folios 1v.1 70r.7.  Tr. by Jinamitra, Surendrabodhi and Ye shes sde.  Marked as chapter six of the Ratnakūṭa.</note>
<note>EoB.  Has noteerences to Chinese versions.  It is supposed to be the oldest extant scripture noteerring to Pure Land.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Akṣobhyavyūha.</title>
<note>Jean Dantinne, La splendeur de l'inébraniable (Akṣobhyavyūha (Tome I, Chapitres I III): les auditeurs (Śrāvaka) (Louvain la Neuve 1983).  Reviewed by J.W. de Jong in Indo Iranian Journal, vol. 29 (1986), pp. 60 63. A French translation of part only.</note>
<note>Jan Nattier, The Indian Roots of Pure Land Buddhism: Insights from the Oldest Chinese Versions of the Larger Sukhāvatīvyūha, Pacific World, third series no. 5 (Fall 2003), pp. 179 202.</note>
<note>Jan Nattier, The Realm of Akṣobhya: A Missing Piece in the History of Pure Land Buddhism, Journal of the International Association of Buddhist Studies, vol. 23, no. 1 (2000), pp. 71 102.</note>
<note>Kurt Tropper, Die Akṣobhyavyūhasūtra Inschrift in Alchi. Ein Beitrag zur Kanjurforschung, Master's thesis (Vienna 1996).</note>
<note>KCDS, p. 43.  A palmleaf Sanskrit manuscript belonging to the Potala.  'Composed' (?) by Dge slong Rdo rje.  The title differs.</note>
<note>Nakamura, p. 178.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Alagaddūpama Sutta.</title>
<note>Kamaleswar Bhattacharya, Once More on a Passage of the Alagaddūpama sutta, contained in:  Petra Kieffer Pülz + Jens Uwe Hartman, eds., Bauddhavidyāsudhākaraḥ:  Studies in Honour of Heinz Bechert on the Occasion of His 65th Birthday, Indica et Tibetica no. 30 (Swisttal Odendorf 1997), pp. 25 28.</note>
<note>Jonardon Ganeri, Why Truth? The Snake Sūtra, Contemporary Buddhism, vol. 3, no. 2 (2002), pp. 127 139.  Similes of the snake and the raft.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Alapañcanamañjuśrīsādhana.</title>
<note>Matsunami, p. 288.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>*Ālikāliguhyācintya...</title>
<note>(Ā li kā li gsang ba bsam gyis mi khyab pa chu klung chen po'i rgyud).  Found in the collected works of Bo dong pa, the Zhi byed Collection, and the Gdams ngag mdzod, but not in the Kanjurs.</note>
<note>Davidson, KCN, p. 77, simply calls it an apocryphal work, based on Completion Stage yoga.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>T402</rkts>
<title>Alimanmathasādhana</title>
<note>(Bung ba myos pa'i sgrub thabs).  Tôh. no. 3467.  Dergé Tanjur, vol. MU, folios 119v.4 120v.4.  Tr. by Grags pa rgyal mtshan.  Drunken bees sādhana.</note>
<note>EoB.  Cordier attributes authorship to Ratnāṅkura (Rin chen myu gu).</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Aliyavasa.</title>
<note>One of the texts recommended by Aśoka in an inscription.  The title in Sanskrit would be Āryavāsā.  Bhattacharya, BTRA.</note>
<note>Barua, Note, p. 807.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>*Ālokavikāsa Sūtra</title>
<note>(Snang ba rol pa'i mdo).</note>
<note>In the list of 21 texts introduced to Tibet in early 7th century by Thon mi Sambhoṭa (Mdo rgyud nyer gcig), according to the Mkhas pa'i dga' ston (oldest source is probably the Ma ṇi bka' 'bum or Bka' chems ka khol ma); see Lahuli, Thon mi, p. 54.</note>
<note>Davidson, KCN, p. 77.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K330</rkts>
<title>Alpadevatāsūtra</title>
<note>(Lha'i mdo nyung ngu).  Tôh. no. 330.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. SA, folios 258v.7 259v.3.  Tr. by Ye shes sde.  Preceded by Devatāsūtra.</note>
<note>EoB.</note>
<note>Adelheid Mette, Zwei kleine Fragments aus Gilgit: I—Tathāgatabimbakārāpaṇasūtra (Gilgit manuscript no 18); II—Devatāsūtra and Alpadevatāsūtra (aus Gilgit manuscript no 13), Studien zur Indologie und Iranistik, vol. 7 (1981), pp. 133 151.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Alpavyutpatti.</title>
<note>Halkias, 'Phang thang, p. 50.  The shorter of the three Vyutpatti treatises, it is considered to be lost.  It is believed that it contained standardizations for terms having to do with measurement.  Perhaps that made it inconvenient for later generations that did not want to follow those standards?  (Just a speculation!)</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Amanasikārakrama.</title>
<note>BSM, p. 16 (MBB II 144).  A 5 folio palmleaf manuscript.</note>
<note>The Tibetan title, if there were one, would very probably be *Yid la mi byed pa'i rim pa.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ambaracakravartisarvaṃdadāvadāna.</title>
<note>A chapter from the  Mahajjātakamālā.  Matsunami, p. 234.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ambarasya Dharmavaśavartīśvaratathāgatavyākaraṇa.</title>
<note>Matsunami, p. 233.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ambāṣṭa Sūtra.</title>
<note>Fumio Enomoto, Jens Uwe Hartmann, Hisashi Matsumura, Sanskrit Texte aus dem buddhistischen Kanon: Neuentdeckungen und Neueditionen, Vandenhoeck and Ruprecht (Göttingen 1989).</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Ambattha Sutta.</title>
<note>Michel Clasquin, Real Buddhas Don't Laugh: Attitudes towards Humour and Laughter in Ancient India + China, Social Identities, vol. 7, no. 1 (2001), pp. 97 116, at p. 108.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Amighasya Samantabhadrabodhisattva jñānavajravijṛmbhiteśvaraketu-nāma-tathāgatavyākaraṇa.</title>
<note>Matsunami, p. 233.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Amiṅghanāmno rājaputrasya akṣobhya tathāgatavyākaraṇa.</title>
<note>Matsunami, p. 233.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K671</rkts>
<title>Amitābhadhāraṇīmantra</title>
<note>(Bcom ldan 'das snang ba mtha' yas kyi gzungs sngags).  Tôh. no. 677 (also, no. 864).  Dergé Kanjur, vol. BA, folio 222v.1 222v.6.</note>
<note>EoB under "Bhagavadamitābhadhāraṇīmantra."</note>
<note>Matsunami, p. 288 (Amitābhadhāraṇī).</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K672</rkts>
<title>*Amitābhānusmṛti</title>
<note> (Snang ba mtha' yas rjes su dran pa).  Tôh. no. 678 (also, no. 867).  Dergé Kanjur, vol. BA, folios 222v.6 223r.1.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts>K49</rkts>
<title>Amitābhavyūha-nāma-mahāyānasūtra</title>
<note> ('Phags pa 'od dpag med kyi bkod pa zhes bya ba theg pa chen po'i mdo).  Tôh. no. 49.  Dergé Kanjur, vol. KA, folios 237v.1 270r.5.  Tr. by Jinamitra, Dānaśīla and Ye shes sde.  This is marked as chapter five of the Ratnakūṭa.</note>
<note>EoB.  Discussion of Sanskrit manuscripts and Chinese translations.  There is also a discussion of its content.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Amitārtha Sūtra.</title>
<note>EoB.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Amitāyurbuddhadhyānasūtra.</title>
<note>Nakamura, p. 207.</note>
</item>

<item>
<rkts></rkts>
<title>Amitāyurdhyānasūtra.</title>
<note>Nakamura, pp. 172, 203.</note>
<note>EoB.  Translated into Chinese by Kālayaśas in 424 CE.</note>
<note>Donald S. Lopez, ed., Buddhism in Practice, Princeton University Press (Princeton 1995), pp. 362, 365, 367, 427, 593, 594, 596.</note>
</item>
####
 
</list>
